https://www.wcp-architects.com/privacy-policy/

Remote ConsultancyAboutNewsCompany HistoryPeopleFAQsDownloadsReviewsLocationsPortfolioServicesArchitectsBuilding SurveyorsHistoric Building ConsultantsExpert WitnessRemote ConsultancyLegal & Other ServicesContact HomePrivacy PolicyPrivacy PolicyWhitworth (“We”) are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.This policy sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it.Your Privacy is Important to usThis notice informs you how we use the information you give us and how we protect your privacy.  It also explains your rights under the UK Data Protection Act (update 2018) and the EU General Data Protection Regulations 2018.  We abide by UK Law and our data protection regulator within the UK is the Information Commissioners Office.Collecting of and purpose for your informationWe offer services such as Building Surveys, Architecture and Consultancy for our clients. To provide such a service, we may need to collect personal data such as name, address, contact details.We use information held about you in the following ways:Your information may be used to introduce you to the services we offer, to help with ongoing administration, to contact you with any review or changes that are applicable, for our own business research and analysis.To ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.To provide you with information, products or services that you request from us or which we feel may interest you, where you have consented to be contacted for such purposes.To carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us.To allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so.To notify you about changes to our service.Withholding of the required data may result in an insufficient service being provided.We may obtain data from individual customers or from employer firms.Sharing your dataWe may share your personal data with the following organisations –We may verify your identity by searching publicly available records held by credit reference agenciesBusiness partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with themWe will not sell or share your information with any other third parties unless we have obtained additional consent from you.Your rights regarding your dataWe will not hold your information for any longer than is necessary and as a maximum no longer than 5 years after you have terminated as a client of our firm unless there is a lawful basis for retentionShould your data be inaccurate we will rectify this without delayShould you wish us to delete your data at any point, please contact the office as shown further below to make the request. This will be actioned unless there is a lawful basis for us to retain the information in which case you will be advised accordinglyShould you wish to transfer your data to another organisation, please contact the office as below and we will organise this for youYou can request access to your data at any time. We will provide you with a full copy within one month of your requestYou can withdraw consent to us holding and processing your information at any time. Please contact the office as below should you wish to do thisWe may provide you with updates and bulletins which are appropriate to your service on an ongoing basis – this will be explained to you if it is applicable. You can opt out of these should you wish to – contact us and advise us if you wish toSecurityWe have in place a full information security policy, business continuity and disaster recovery plans. We take data security very seriously and have in place we feel the most secure options available to store and transfer your data securely.  We can provide details on request.Where we store your personal data:The data that we collect from you may be transferred to, and stored at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff maybe engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.Our contact detailsShould you wish to contact us in relation to any issues within this notice, please contact:Data Protection Officer Whitworth 18 Hatter Street, Bury St Edmunds, Suffolk, IP33 1NE United KingdomYou will be responded to as promptly as possibleYour right to complainShould you wish to make a complaint in relation to data protection issues relating to our firm, you can contact us as above or you can contact our regulator as follows:The Information Commissioner’s OfficeWycliffe House, Water Lane, Wilmslow, Cheshire, SK9 5AFTel: 0303 123 1113 (local rate) or 01625 545 745 if you prefer to use a national rate numberwww.ico.org.ukConsentWe are required under the Regulations to obtain your consent to our collection, processing, sharing and holding of your personal data.  Please ensure you have read this notice fully and accept all that it contains.  If you have any queries, please contact us directly. Please contact us should you not be able to read or understand this notice sufficiently.Changes to our privacy policyAny changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by e-mail.ContactQuestions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to info@whitworth.co.uk All operations are continuing in accordance with COVID-19 guidelines, this includes accepting new architectural and surveying enquiries.
